Guide to the Rochambeau Papers and Rochambeau Family Cartographic Archive
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Map Collection of the Comte de Rochambeau, 1695-1792; Series V; 5.25; (13 boxes)
  - AMERICAN REVOLUTION
    - IK 360 Portfolio of Maps [of North America].
      - No. 14 Pennsylvania. Paris: Le Rouge., n.d.
        Title and/or other information taken from map: A MAP OF/PENNSYLVANIA/EXHIBITING/not only THE IMPROVED PARTS of that PROVINCE, but also/ITS EXTENSIVE FRONTIERS:/Laid down FROM ACTUAL SURVEYS/and Chiefly FROM THE LATE MAP of W. Scull Publisbed in 1770;/And Humbly Inscribed/TO THE HONOURABLE/THOMAS PENN AND RICHARD PENN ESQUIRES/TRUE AND ABSOLUTE PROPRIETARIES & GOVERNORS OF THE/PROVINCE OF PENNSYLVANIA/and the TERRITORIES thereunto belonging/[and] LA PENSILVANIE/en trois Feuilles/Traduite des meilleures Cartes anglaises/ A Paris/Chéz le Rouge rue des Grands Augustins/avec Privilege du Roi
        Notes: Linen-backed. Colored. 27 3/8 x 54 11/16 inches. There is another copy of this map, also colored - see IK 371, map no. 3, parts 1-3.
        SEE: Oversize Bound Volumes, box 37, folder 644.
    - Plan of Different Camps Occupied by Rochambeau's Army., n.d. (Box 18, Folder 455)
      Campaign of 1781, June 10 - September 27, 1781. Series of 34 manuscript plans, entitled "Amerique Campagne 1781 Plans des differents camps occupes par L'Armee aux ordres de Mr. Le Comte De Rochambeau." 35 pages, folio, the maps in pen and ink and colors; color key on the title. Attributed to Louis-Alexandre and Charles-Louis Berthier.
      It should be noted that a similar collection of plans, for the period of July 1 - Dec. 2, 1782, is in the Library of Congress (described in Phillips, List of Geographical Atlases, Vol. I, pp. 734-736).
  - COMMAND OF PICARDY AND ARTOIS
    - IK 96 Provinces of Picardy and Artois, by Jean B. Nolin. Paris: Basset., 1785
      Map tab inscription: Picardie/Artois/1785/[and] IK/96.
      Inscribed on map: picardie et artois
      Title and/or other information taken from map: CARTE/DES PROVINCES DE/PICARDIE ET D'ARTOIS,/Gouvernement Militaire de Picardie, Divisé/en ses differents Pays Partie des Gouverne=/mens Militaires de l'Isle de France et des/Pays Bas François./DRESSEE/Sur les dernieres Observations Astronomiques, des/Operations Geometriques de Mrs. de l'Academie/Royale des Sciences/Par J B Nolin Geographe/A PARIS/Chez Basset rue St. Jacques./Avec privilege du Roy/ 1785.
      Notes: Uncolored. 21 7/8 x 32 3/16 inches.
      SEE: Oversize Broadside Case, folder 875.
    - IK 115 The Canal of Picardy., n.d.
      Map tab inscription: Canaux de/Picardie [and] IK/115.
      Inscribed on map: canaux du royaume/et de picardie
      Title and/or other information taken from map: [handwritten] Carte des Navigations/& la hollande des pays bas autri-/-chiens, & la flandre françoise, et d'une/partie & la france destinée a faire/connoitre l'utilité dous servis la/jonction & la somme à L'Escours par/le Canal souterrain & Picardie. [and] P.F. Tardieu Sculp
      Notes: Colored. 14 3/4 x 21 7/8 inches.
      SEE: Oversize Boxes, box 49, folder 780.
    - IK 60 Topographical map of Cherbourg by Jean B. Nolin., 1787
      Map tab inscription: Cherbourg/1787 [and] IK/60.
      Inscribed on map: Cherbourg
      Title and/or other information taken from map: CARTE TOPOGRAPHIQUE DU PORT ET DE LA VILLE/DE CHERBOURG/ET DE SES ENVIRONS/Levées sur les Lieux Par J.G.B. Ingenieur Geographe./1787
      Notes: Colored. 22 3/4 x 31 3/4 inches.
      SEE: Oversize Broadside Case, folder 876.
    - IK 61 Map of Cherbourg., 1786
      Map tab inscription: Cherbourg/1786 [and] IK/61.
      Inscribed on map: cherbourg [and] port de cherbourg
      Title and/or other information taken from map: [handwritten] CARTE/dela Rade de Cherbourg et des Environs, où l'on Voit le tracé/dela digue pour fermer cette rade, 1786.
      Notes: Watercolor manuscript map. 23 3/16 x 33 5/8 inches.
      SEE: Oversize Broadside Case, folder 877.
    - IK 68 Plan of Luxembourg., 1774
      Map tab inscription: [top part missing]/IK/68.
      Title and/or other information taken from map: [handwritten] PLAN de/luxembourg/1774
      Notes: Watercolor manuscript map. 14 1/2 x 18 5/8 inches.
      SEE: Oversize Boxes, box 49, folder 781.
    - IK 32 Dunkerque, Calais, Boulogne, Saint Omer by Cassini. Paris: Vignon Marchand. (Box 18, Folder 456-459)
      Maps originally stored together. See also: Oversize Sleeve Boxes, box 51. Maps measure 8 x 5 1/4 inches, folded.
      1) Map 1: Dunkerque
      Map tab inscription on map no. 1 (part 1 of 4): No.6/Dunkerque
      Inscribed on label laid down on map no. 1 (part 1 of 4): No. 6 flle/14/l. Dunkerque [and] IK/32.
      Title and/or other information taken from map no. 1 (part 1 of 4): [from circular label laid down on front of map] a Paris/Chez Vignon Marchand/de Cartes de Géographie,/rue Dauphine vis-à-vis/celle d'Anjou. [and, on map proper] F. [raised part covered over] 14
      Notes: This is the upper half portion of a map; the bottom half is listed below under part 4. Linen-backed. Uncolored. 23 x 36 inches.
      2) Map 2: Pas-de-Calais
      Map tab inscription on map no. 2 (part 2 of 4): No. 21/Pas de Calais
      Inscribed on label laid down on map no. 2 (part 2 of 4): No. 21. flle 7/2. Pas de Calais
      Title and/or other information taken from map no. 2 (part 2 of 4): [and from circular label laid down on front of map] a Paris/Chez Vignon Marchand/de Cartes de Geographie/rue Dauphine vis-à-vis/celle d'Anjou.
      Notes: This is an upper portion of a map; the lower portion is listed below under part 3. Linen-backed. Uncolored. 23 1/2 x 20 7/8 inches.
      3) Map 3: Boulogne
      Map tab inscription on map no. 3 (part 3 of 4): No. 22/Boulogne
      Inscribed on label laid down on map no. 3 (part 3 of 4): No. 22 flle/16/3. Boulogne
      Title and/or other information taken from map no. 3 (part 3 of 4): 1758. [and] Le Roy le Jeune coralt [and from circular label laid down on front of map] a Paris/ Chez Vignon Marchand/de Cartes de Geographie/rue Dauphine vis-à-vis/celle d'Anjou.
      Notes: This is a lower portion of a map; the upper portion is listed above under part 2. Linen-backed. Uncolored. 23 1/2 x 20 3/4 inches.
      4) Map 4: Saint Omer - Paris 1744-93
      Map tab inscription on map no. 4 (part 4 of 4): No. 5/st Omer
      Inscribed on label laid down on map no. 4 (part 4 of 4): No. 5 flle 19/4. St. Omer.
      Title and/or other information taken from map no. 4 (part 4 of 4): 1758. [and, inscribed on Map proper] No. 5 [and, from circular label laid down on front of map] a Paris/Chez Vignon Marchand/de Cartes de Géographie,/rue Dauphine vis-à-vis/celle d/Anjou.
      Notes: This is the lower half portion of a map; the top portion is listed above as part 1. Linen-backed. Uncolored. 23 3/16 x 36 1/8 inches.
    - IK 130 Map of the Low Countries by Guillaume de L'Isle. Paris: Dezauche., 1780 (Box 18, Folder 460)
      Inscribed on label laid down on map: IK/130./[and] hollande
      Title and/or other information taken from map: CARTE/DES PROVINCES UNIES/DES PAYS BAS./Tirée des Cartes les plus correcte/qui en ont été faites sur les lieux./Rectifiées par les Observations/et Opérations Géométriques de Snellius/et par celles que Mr. Cassini y a faites en dernier lieu./Par G. DE L'ISLE Géographe,/de l'Académie Royale des Sciences./A PARIS,/Chez DEZAUCHE Rue des Noyers près celle des Anglois./avec Privilége du Roy pour 20 ans/ 1780/Gravée par liceaux le fils
      Notes: Linen-backed. Colored. 19 1/2 x 25 3/8 inches.
    - IK 129 Holland. Matthaeus Seutter.
      Inscribed on map: IK/129./[and] hollande
      Title and/or other information taken from map: TABULA COMITATUS/HOLLANDIAE/in Praefecturas suas distributa;/cui adjuncta est/PROVINC. ULTRAIECTINA/et maxima pars/GELDRIAE/ sumo studio delin. et aeri incidit/MATTHAEUS SEUTTER/ S.C.M. GEOGRAPH. AUG./[and] cum Priv. S.R.I. Vicariatus.
      Notes: Colored. 23 x 28 3/4 inches.
      SEE: Oversize Broadside Case, folder 878.
    - IK 116 Environs of Dunkerque, Gravelines and Saint Omer. Paris: Crépy.
      Map tab inscription: 1743/Environs de Dunkerque/gravelines, St Omer/etc/IK/116.
      Title and/or other information taken from map: CARTE DES ENVIRONS DE DUNKERQUE, BERGUE, GRAVELINES, ST. OMER, AIRE, LILLE, MENIN, YPRES, DIXMUDE, &C./en 1743 [and] Dressée sur les Memoires de Eugene Henry Friex [and] A Paris Chez Crepy rue St. Jacques a St. Pierre
      SEE: Oversize Broadside Case, folder 879.
    - IK 107 Environs of Kortrijk, Audenaarde, Mons. Paris: Crépy., 1743
      Map tab inscription: 1743/Environs de/Courtray,/Oudenarde,/ Mons etc/[and] IK/107
      Title and/or other information taken from map: CARTE PARTICULIERE DES ENVIRONS DE COURTRAY, OUDENARDE, MONS, TOURNAY, ATH, NINOVE, ALOST, ORCHIES, &C./1743./[and] Dressé sur les Memoires de Eugene henry Friex./[and] a Paris Chez Crepy rue St. Jacques a limage S. Pierre.
      SEE: Oversize Broadside Case, folder 880.
    - IK 34bis Plan of Rochefort. Paris., n.d.
      Inscribed on map: IK/34bis/[and] Rochefort./[and] Plans de Prague-et de Rochefort
      Title and/or other information taken from map: PLAN/DE ROCHEFORT,/...A Paris chés Longchamps Géographe, rue St. Jacques, à la Place des Victoires./L'on trouve chés l'Auteur une Carte detaillée en 2 feuilles, du Pays/ d'Aunis et de la Saintonge.
      Notes: Uncolored. 22 3/4 X 32 inches.
      SEE: Oversize Broadside Case, folder 881.
  - COMMAND OF ALSACE
    - IK 71 Alsace. Matthaeus Seutter.
      Map tab inscription: Alsace/[and] IK/71.
      Inscribed on map: Carte d'alzace en allement
      Title and/or other information taken from map: ALSATIA/ LANDGRAVIATUS/cum utroque/MARCHIONATU BADENSI,/SUNDGOVIA BRISGOVIA,/magno tractu Herciniae Silvae/et ditione/IV. URBIUM SILVESTRIUM/Cura et Sumtibus/MATTH. SEUTTERI, S.C.M.G. AUGUST./Cu Grat. et Pr. S.R.I. Vicariatg, in partibg/Rheni, Suevice, et Juris Franconici.
      Notes: Colored. 25 3/4 x 22 3/4 inches.
      SEE: Oversize Broadside Case, folder 882.
    - IK 74 Strasbourg., 1760
      Map tab inscription: Strasbourg/[and] IK/74.
      Inscribed on map: Plan de Strasbourg/[and] plan de Strasbourg/[and] plans de Strasbourg
      Title and/or other information taken from map: Strasbourg/ Avec les Environs./1760.
      Notes: Watercolor manuscript map. 28 x 47 1/4 inches.
      SEE: Oversize Rolled Maps, folder 901.
    - IK 72 Neuf Brisach., n.d.
      Map tab inscription: Neuf Brisack/[and] IK/72.
      Inscribed on map: Brisack
      Title and/or other information taken from map: PLAN DU NEUF BRISACK
      Notes: Watercolor manuscript map. 20 1/4 x 26 inches.
      SEE: Oversize Boxes, box 49, folder 782.
    - IK 165 Huningue., n.d.
      Map tab inscription: Huningue/[and] IK/165.
      Inscribed on map: Huningue/[and] huningue et neubrisaque/ [and] huninque et neubrisaque et Strasbourg
      Title and/or other information taken from map: PLAN D'HUNINGUE
      Notes: Watercolor manuscript map. 26 3/16 x 20 3/16 inches.
      SEE: Oversize Boxes, box 49, folder 783.
    - IK 64 Map of the Main Roads of Alsace., n.d. (Box 18, Folder 461)
      Inscribed on map: IK/64 Carte---[illegible]/province de Alsace/[and] Alsace
      Title and/or other information taken from map: CARTE/DES GRANDES ROUTES/ET/PRINCIPALES COMUNICATIONS/DE LA/PROVINCE D'ALSACE./[and] Gravé par Weis.
      Notes: Linen-backed. Colored. 15 3/4 X 32 5/8 inches overall. 8 x 4 3/4 inches folded.
  - JOURNEY TO SWITZERLAND
    - IK 305 The Duchies of Savoy, of Chablais, and of Geneva. Paris: Nicolas de Fer., 1709
      Inscribed on map: IK/305./[and] Suisse/[and] Suisse
      Title and/or other information taken from map: LES DUCHEZ DE SAVOYE, DE CHABLAIS, ET DE GENEVOIS, LES COMTEZ/DE MAURIENNE, ET DE TARANTAISE, ET LA BARONIE DE FAUSIGNY./ Connues sous le nom de/SAVOYE./Dressée sur divers Memoires Par N. de Fer/[and] A PARIS/chez le Sr. de Fer. Geographe de sa Majesté catholique/et de Monseigneur le Dauphin. dans l'Isle du Palais sur/le quay de l'Orloge a la Sphere Royale. Avec Privilege du Roy. 1709.
      Notes: Colored. 23 1/2 x 18 3/4 inches.
      SEE: Oversize Boxes, box 49, folder 784.
    - IK 306 Switzerland. Paris: Jean B. Nolin., 1746
      Inscribed on map: IK/306./[and] Les Suisses leurs alliés et/les Sujets des Suisses
      Title and/or other information taken from map: LES SUISSES,/Leurs ALLIEZ;/Auec les Sujets des Suisses, et des Alliez./selon les Memoires de Simler, de Gyger, et de/ plusieurs Autres Autheurs, par le Sr. TILLEMON/A PARIS/ Chés J. B. Nolin Geographe, rue St. Jacques à l'Enseigne/ de la Place des Victoires. Avec Privilege du Roy. 1746
      SEE: Oversize Broadside Case, folder 883.
    - IK 310 Fribourg. Paris: Bailleul le jeune., n.d.
      Inscribed on map: IK/310./[and] fribourg/[and] Suisse
      Title and/or other information taken from map: PLAN/de la Ville et Forts de/FRIBOURG/en Brisgaw./[and] A Paris chez le Sr. Bailleul le jeune rue St Sevrin au Soleil d'Or
      Notes: Uncolored. 20 13/16 x 28 inches.
      SEE: Oversize Boxes, box 49, folder 785.
    - IK 41 France Divided into 9 regions by Robert de Hesseln. Paris., 1786 (Box 18, Folder 462)
      Inscribed on map: FRANCE/1786 [and] IK/41./[and] France - ? [illegible]
      Title and/or other information taken from map: PREMIERE CARTE/DE LA NOUVELLE TOPOGRAPHIE/CONTENANT LA FRANCE DIVISÉE/EN IX RÉGIONS;/SES PROVINCES, SES COURS SOUVERAINES; et le/TABLEAU GÉNÉRAL/des Carrés ou Portions uniformes du terrein employées/dans cette Description détaillée du Royaume/par M. DE HESSELN, Censeur royal et Géog. de la Ville de PARIS./1786.
      Notes: Linen-backed. Colored. 21 3/4 x 21 5/8 inches overall. 7 1/2 x 7 1/2 inches folded.
  - ARMY OF THE NORTH: BRABANT CAMPAIGN
    - IK 91 United Provinces of th Low Countries. Paris: Basset., 1785
      Map tab inscription: Hollande/et/Brabant/1785/[and] IK/91.
      Inscribed on map: La hollande et partie du Brabant
      Title and/or other information taken from map: PROVINCES- UNIES DES PAYS-BAS/avec leurs Acquisitions/DANS LA FLANDRE, LE BRABANT, LE LIMBOURG/ET LE LYEGE/Par le Sr. SANSON. Géographe ordinaire du Roy./Corrigée et Augmentée en 1785/PAR L. DENIS/Géographe et Auteur du Conducteur Français./[and] A PARIS, Chez Basset Rue St. Jacques au coin de celle des/Mathurins, à l'Image Ste. Genevieve./ [and] Cordier, Sculp:
      Notes: Colored. 21 11/16 x 31 5/8 inches.
      SEE: Oversize Broadside Case, folder 884.
    - IK 88 The Provinces of the Catholic Low Countries. Paris: Basset., 1785
      Map tab inscription: 1785/Pays-Bas [and] IK/88.
      Inscribed on map: Pays Bas
      Title and/or other information taken from map: LES PROVINCES DES PAYS-BAS CATHOLIQUES/destinguées suivant qu'elles sont presentement partagées entre/LE ROY DE FRANCE, LE ROY D'ESPAGNE/et les Estats Generaux des Provinces-Vnies./PAR H. JAILLOT/Corrigée et augmentée /en 1785/PAR. L. DENIS/Géographe et auteur du Conducteur Français./[and] A PARIS chés Basset, Rüe St. Jacques au/ coin de celle des Mathurins à l'Image Ste./Genevieve./Il tient Magasin de Papiers/en Rouleaux./[and] LES PROVINCES DES PAYS BAS CATHOLIQUES, restées pour la pluspart sous l'obeissance du Roy d'Espagne sc? les DUCHÉS DE BRABANT, LIMBO/ANVERS, et LA SEIGNEURIE DE MALINES, ou sont exactement distinguées toutes les Conquestes de Sa Majesté Tres-Chrestienne, reunies a la Couronne de/-vnies dans la FLANDRE, le BRABANT, et le LIMBOURG, ou sont encor L'ARCHEVESCHÉ DE CAMBRAY, des Conquestes du Roy: et L'EVESCHÉ DE LYEGE possedé par
      Notes: This is a portion of a map. Uncolored. 29 7/8 x 21 3/8 inches.
      SEE: Oversize Boxes, box 49, folder 786.
    - IK 93 Bolsduc. Paris: Le Rouge., n.d.
      Map tab inscription: 1795/Bolsduc [and] IK/93.
      Title and/or other information taken from map: BOLSDUC/a Paris/chés le Rouge. ruë des gds./Augustins
      Notes: Uncolored. 15 15/16 x 22 7/8 inches.
      SEE: Oversize Boxes, box 49, folder 787.
    - IK 95 Map of Flanders. Paris: Basset., 1790
      Map tab inscription: Flandre/1790/[and] IK/95
      Title and/or other information taken from map: CARTE DES/ PAYS BAS CATHOLIQUES/connu. sous le nom de/FLANDRE/DIVISÉE ENTRE LA COURONNE DE FRANCE,/LA MAISON D'AUTRICHE, ET/LES PROVINCES UNIES./Dressée sur les observations de Mrs de/ l Academie Royale des Sciences/A PARIS, chez Basset, rue St/Jacques, au coin de celle des/Mathurins, à l'Image de/ Ste Genevieve 1790./[and] Gravé par Laurent
      Notes: Uncolored. 21 5/8 x 32 1/4 inches.
      SEE: Oversize Broadside Case, folder 885.
    - IK 40 France Divided Into 85 Departments. Paris: Desnos., 1792
      Map tab inscription: Desnos/Nouvelle carte/d France/ divisée en/85 départs/1792
      Inscribed on map: IK/40./[and] France/1792
      Title and/or other information taken from map: NOUVELLE CARTE/DE FRANCE/DIVISÉE EN 85 DÉPARTEMENTS/DRESSÉE D'APRES LES OBSERVATIONS DE MR/DE L'ACADEMIE NATLE DES SCIENCES,/ Conformément aux Décrets de l'Assemblée/Nationale, Sanctionné en 1792./AVEC LES PRINCIPALES ROUTES DU ROYAUME/ DEDIÉE AUX VOYAGEURS./A PARIS/Chez le Cn Desnos, Ingénieur- Géographe/et Libraire des Etats de Danemark,/rue St. Jacques au Globe,/No. 254.
      Notes: Colored. 22 3/4 x 30 inches.
      SEE: Oversize Broadside Case, folder 886.
    - E 337 The Antilles. Paris: Le Rouge., 1779
      There are thirteen maps, one folding, bound together in marbled boards. The front cover is inscribed: Cartes des antilles. The spine height measures 21 1/4 inches. The flyleaf is inscribed: E. The first map in this group (LES ANTILLES) is inscribed E/337. This volume is in a light blue cloth box case with a black leather label on spine lettered in gold: LE ROUGE/MAPS OF THE/ANTILLES, BERMUDA, AND/VIRGIN ISLANDS/1779. The spine height of the box-case is 23 1/8 inches.
      The maps are bound as follows:
      No. 1: LES ANTILLES/et la/GUAYANNE/Par la Rochette/1776/ Traduit de l'Anglais/A PARIS/Chéz Le Rouge Ingr. Geogr du Roi/Rue des Gds. Augustins/1779/Avec Privilége du Roi
      Notes to No. 1: Inscribed E/337. Colored. 29 5/8 x 24 15/16 inches.
      No. 2: LES/BERMUDES/Levées par Lampriere/Déterminées Astronomiquement/à Londres en 1775./Traduit de l'Anglois./ A PARIS/Chés Le Rouge Ingen. Géographe du Roi rue des grands Augustins/1779/Avec Privilege du Roi.
      Notes to No. 2: Uncolored. 21 3/16 x 29 1/2 inches.
      No. 3: LES ISLES TURQUES/d'aprés les Levées de 1753./par le Sloop l'Aigle et l'Emeraude/par ordre du Gouverneur de St. Domingue/corrigées sur les Observations de Ed: Hawke/ faites en 1770. dans le Shooner Royal./Publié a Londres en 1775./Traduit A PARIS/Chez le Rouge en 1779.
      Notes to No. 3: Uncolored. 21 1/8 x 15 5/8 inches.
      No. 4: LES VIERGES,/Levées/PAR LES ANGLAIS,/et/PAR LES DANNOIS,/Traduit de l'Anglais./A PARIS,/Chez le Sr. Le Rouge, rue des Grands Augustins,/1779.
      Notes to No. 4: Colored. 21 3/16 x 29 5/8 inches.
      No. 5: ISLE/ST CHRISTOPHE/OU/ST KITTS/Levé/Par Ant: Ravell Chevalier/Arpenteur Général/des Isles de St. Christophe, Nevis et Montserrat,/Par Jefferys en 1775,/Traduit de l'Anglais./A PARIS./Par le Rouge Ingr Geographe du Roi/rue des Grands Augustins/1779./avec Privilege du Roi.
      Notes to No. 5: Uncolored. 21 1/4 x 29 1/2 inches.
      No 6: ANTIGUE,/Levée/par/Robert Baker,/Arpenteur Général de l'Isle./Traduit de l'Anglais./A PARIS/Chez le Rouge rue des Gds. Augustins/1779./avec Privilege du Roi.
      Notes to No. 6: Uncolored. 21 3/16 x 29 1/2, inches.
      No. 7: STE LUCIE/D'après les Plans levés par les Anglois/ lors qu'ils la possedoient./Par Jefferys en 1775./Traduit de l'Anglois/A PARIS/Par le Rouge, Rue des grands Augustins./1779/Avec Privilege du Roi.
      Notes to No. 7: Inscribed: St lucie Uncolored. 29 1/2 x 21 3/16 inches.
      No. 8: LA BARBADE/Levée/par G: Mayo./Gravée par Jefferys/A PARIS/Chez le Rouge rue des grands Augustins./1779.
      Notes to No. 8: Uncolored. 29 1/2 x 21 3/16 inches.
      No. 9: BEQUIA/OU/BECOUYA,/la plus Septentrionale/des/ GRANADILLES,/Leve en 1763.
      Notes to No. 9: Uncolored. 15 5/8 x 21 1/8, inches.
      No. 10: TABAGO/Dressé sur des Arpentages nouveaux/Par JEFFERYS en 1775./Traduit de l'Anglois./A PARIS./Par le ROUGE Ingenieur Geographe du Roi; Rue des grands Augustins./avec Privilege du Roi 1779.
      Notes to No. 10: Uncolored. 21 1/8 x 29 5/8 inches.
      No. 11: Curaçao/Tiré/des Originaux Hollandois/de Van Keulen/Dressé sur les dernieres Observations/A PARIS Traduit de l'Anglais/Chez le Rouge rue des Gds. Augustins/ 1779.
      Notes to No. 11: Uncolored. 21 1/8 x 29 1/2 inches.
      No. 12: RUATAN OU RATTAN/LEVÉ/PAR HENRY BARNSLEY LIEUTENANT/Augmenté/Par JEFFERYS en 1775./Traduit de l'Anglais./A PARIS/Chés LE ROUGE Ingr Géographe Ordre du Roi, Rue des Gds. Augustins/1779./avec Privilege du Roi.
      Notes to No. 12: Uncolored. 21 1/8 x 29 3/4 inches.
      No. 13: LA MARTINIQUE/par les Ingenieurs Anglais/lorsqu'ils en étoient possesseurs/par Jefferys 1775./A PARIS/Chez le Rouge Ingr Géographe du Roi/Rue des Grands Augustins./ 1779./avec Privilege du Roi.
      Notes to No. 13: Uncolored. 21 1/8 x 29 3/8 inches.
      SEE: Oversize Bound Volumes, box 38, folder 645.
- Map Collection of the Vicomte de Rochambeau, 1702-1823; Series VI; 7; (17 boxes)
  Series VI, Map Collection of the Vicomte de Rochambeau, is organized into eight subseries: American Islands, Italian Campaign and Command of Liguria, Prisoner in England, Central European Campaigns, French and European Campaigns, Spanish and Portuguese Campaigns, Russian Campaign, German Campaign.
  - AMERICAN ISLANDS
    - IK 408 The British Isles by Janvier. Paris: Lattré., 1791
      Inscribed on map: IK/408/[and] Iles Britannique/[and] Carte d'Angleterre./[and] Angleterre
      Title and/or other information taken from map: LES ISLES BRITANNIQUES/Comprenant les Royaumes/D'ANGLETERRE D'ECOSSE ET D'IRLANDE/DIVISÉS EN GRANDES PROVINCES/Subdivisés par Comtés/Dressés sur les Observations Astronomiques,/Par le Sr. Janvier Geographe./A PARIS/Chés Lattré Graveur rue S. Jacques au coin de celle de la Parcheminerie à la Ville de Bordeaux./Avec Privilege du Roy. 1791./[and] Choffard. fecit.
      Notes: Colored. 21 1/2 x 28 1/4 inches. There is a copy of this map, dated 1769 - see IK 323, also colored.
      SEE: Oversize Boxes, box 50, folder 788.
    - IK 382 Guadeloupe. Paris: Le Rouge., n.d. (Box 19, Folder 463)
      Inscribed on label laid down on map: IK/382./[and] La Guadeloupe.
      Title and/or other information taken from map: LA GUADELOUPE/DEDIÉE/A MGR. CHARLES PHILIPPE D'ALBERT DUC DE LUYNES,/Pair de France Chevalier Commandeur des Ordres du Roy,/Seigneur Usufruitier, du Duché de Chevreuse, des Comtés/de Montfort, Prevôté, et Seigneurie d'Houdan y réunis,/Marquis de Dangeau Baron de St. Hermine et autres Lieux./Par son très humble et très Obeissant Serviteur/Le Rouge Ingr Géographe du Roy./a Paris Rue des Augustins./ MDCCLIII
      Notes: Linen-backed. Colored. 19 3/4 x 24 3/4 inches overall. 7 1/2 x 5 inches, folded.
    - IK 379 Saint Lucia. Paris: Le Rouge., 1779 (Box 19, Folder 464)
      Inscribed on label laid down on map: IK/379./[and] Ste Lucie.
      Title and/or other information taken from map: STE. LUCIE/ D'après les Plans levés par les Anglois/lors qu'ils la possedoient,/Par Jefferys en 1775./Traduit de l'Anglois/A PARIS/Par le Rouge, Rue des grands Augustins./1779/Avec Privilege du Roi.
      Notes: Linen-backed. Uncolored. 24 1/2 x 19 1/8 inches, overall. 7 1/2 x 5 1/4 inches, folded.
    - IK 389 Santo Domingo., n.d.
      Map tab inscription: St. Domingue/[and] IK 389
      Title and/or other information taken from map: ST. DOMINGO/ Capitale de l'Isle du même nom.
      Notes: There is a separate piece of paper with this map on which is written "Les Isles de l'/Amerique"/[and] "Isle de l'Amerique"/[and] Checked 11/23/59